<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Acme on mostlymaths.net</title>
    <link>https://mostlymaths.net/tags/acme/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Acme on mostlymaths.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 20:37:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mostlymaths.net/tags/acme/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mandelbrot set in one line of APL</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2014/01/the-mandelbrot-set-in-one-line-of-apl.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 20:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2014/01/the-mandelbrot-set-in-one-line-of-apl.html/</guid>
      <description>Is this line noise?
⍉&amp;#39; *&amp;#39;[⍎&amp;#39;1+0&amp;lt;|z&amp;#39;,(∊150⍴⊂&amp;#39;←c+m×m&amp;#39;),&amp;#39;←c←(¯2.1J¯1.3+(((2.6÷b-1)×(¯1+⍳b))∘.+(0J1×(2.6÷b-1)×(¯1+⍳b←51))))&amp;#39;] Nope. This is not line noise, but a complete APL program to display the Mandelbrot set in glorious ASCII, with asterisks and spaces just like Brooks and Matelski did a long time ago while studying Kleinian groups (it&amp;rsquo;s a short paper, read it someday). I&amp;rsquo;ll explain in (a lot, I hope) detail this line in a few moments. So, what&amp;rsquo;s APL first?

APL is literally A Programming Language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find Search Engine Rankings... via the Command Line</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2013/05/find-search-engine-rankings-via-command.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 18:33:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2013/05/find-search-engine-rankings-via-command.html/</guid>
      <description>Via pixelfrenzy@flickr
Beware! The software described here is just for personal and very light use. Its use beyond purely recreational value is against Google Search terms of service, and I don&amp;rsquo;t want you or anyone to step that line. Any use of this code is at your own risk.
Well, after this scary paragraph, lets get to the real meat. Which boils down to just a few lines of bash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just as Mario: Using the Plan9 plumber utility</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2013/04/just-as-mario-using-plan9-plumber.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 21:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2013/04/just-as-mario-using-plan9-plumber.html/</guid>
      <description>Note: It&amp;rsquo;s best to open the videos in full screen. Also I have added a few line breaks or readability in the code snippets that will make them not work correctly. It&amp;rsquo;s not hard to find where they are, if you run into any problems let me know.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following this blog, you&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Acme and related Plan 9 from User Space utilities lately. One of its pieces is the plumber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extensibility in the Acme text editor</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2013/03/extensibility-programming-acme-text-editor.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 18:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2013/03/extensibility-programming-acme-text-editor.html/</guid>
      <description>Text editors. You hate them or love them. Praise them with religious zeal, and attack them with the same power. I&amp;rsquo;ve been an emacs user for the last 8 years, getting as deep as I could without checking the source. And the past few months I have started using evil-mode in emacs, to get some taste of vim in my daily editing (mostly text objects.)
There&amp;rsquo;s still a third contestant in editor-land, for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editor Magic: emacs, vim, acme and the return key</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2012/09/editor-magic-emacs-vim-acme-and-return.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 11:02:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2012/09/editor-magic-emacs-vim-acme-and-return.html/</guid>
      <description>Glenda, the Plan 9 bunny. Image copyrighted by Lucent Technologies, hosted by Wikimedia Commons and posted here for information purposes
A few months ago I wrote about how I&amp;rsquo;m using vim in my ipad. You know, I&amp;rsquo;m an emacs guy, just started writing my own (useful) stuff to improve it. Recently I finished gnusnotes.el, a package which allows you to easily add notes to emails. Of course, before this I had already written emacs code, just that it was only for me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>