<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on mostlymaths.net</title>
    <link>https://mostlymaths.net/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on mostlymaths.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 13:03:45 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mostlymaths.net/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2019#23 Readings of the Week</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2019/09/201923-readings-of-the-week.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 13:03:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2019/09/201923-readings-of-the-week.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been on quite the hiatus, making this more of a &lt;em&gt;readings of the month&lt;/em&gt;
edition. Sorry!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2018/01/2017-year-in-review.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 15:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2018/01/2017-year-in-review.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am trying to make these posts a tradition (even if a few days late). I thought 2016 had been a really weird and fun year, but 2017 has beaten it easily. And I only hope 2018 will be even better in every way. For the record, when I say &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt;, it means Laia and me unless explicitly changed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get into the Flow: Music Meditation</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/12/give-yourself-to-music.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 13:15:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/12/give-yourself-to-music.html/</guid>
      <description>From morguefile
It&amp;rsquo;s Friday afternoon after a long day and a long week. You board your train and are lucky to find a seat, soon it is crowded with people standing and chatting. You feel tired after the day, and think just about taking a late afternoon nap upon coming home.
But you plug your earphones, turn up the volume just until you can&amp;rsquo;t hear the train sounds and you are in another place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E30DC: Writing this in Conkeror</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/12/emacs-30-day-challenge-update-1-writing.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/12/emacs-30-day-challenge-update-1-writing.html/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been already a week since I started my emacs 30 day challenge, and it is time for an update on how it is going and what packages I am using. I&amp;rsquo;ll start giving configuration updates along the way, I&amp;rsquo;m still fiddling with them. You can check also my post about using gnus to read mail with Gmail.
Browsing with Conkeror The same day I started my 30 day challenge, the emacs focused blog emacs-fu posted a wonderful article highlighting the conkeror web browser (not to be confused with Konqueror, the standard browser in KDE based desktops).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More #SongsInCode</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/11/more-songsincode.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 00:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/11/more-songsincode.html/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday, 20, all SongsInCode&amp;rsquo;rs were asked to try to get #songsincode trending again to commemorate the 3 months anniversary of the idea. I submitted 3 songs (far less than my first outburst)&amp;hellip; and almost no-one else tried to overwhelm twitter with his songs (a few did, and with great ideas ;)
 KISS - know=&amp;quot;you cry&amp;rdquo;;know++=&amp;quot;Walk street beside her&amp;rdquo;; PassBy(); everybody: puts(&amp;ldquo;Looks good&amp;rdquo;); you: puts(&amp;ldquo;Strutter&amp;rdquo;); goto everybody;
Duran Duran - if(!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Songs In Code</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/10/songs-in-code.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2009 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/10/songs-in-code.html/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I found a page via StumbleUpon, and caught my inner geek. Songs in code, a trend in twitter a few days ago. Other examples here, and here (twitter). Below my own creations.
 (setq My &amp;lsquo;(sleeping)) - Roxette
do{love( );}while(TRUE); - The Beatles
while(1){puts(&amp;ldquo;Young&amp;rdquo;);} - Alphaville
love( ); puts(&amp;ldquo;Now&amp;rdquo;); - Roxette
do{ }while(b*tchslaprappin&amp;amp;&amp;amp;cocainetongue); - Guns N&amp;rsquo; Roses
if(!say){say=MAXINT;} - Ronan Keating
int love=0; if(friday){love=1;} - The Cure</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MP3 to iPod audiobook: personal reminder</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/05/mp3-to-ipod-audiobook-personal-reminder.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/05/mp3-to-ipod-audiobook-personal-reminder.html/</guid>
      <description>New: The previous version is rubbish! Just add your MP3 encoded files to iTunes library, select the entire album, choose get info from right-clicking it, go to the last tab (options) and select: Part of a compilation, remember position, skip when shuffling and in media type, Audibook. And you are done in a moment.
Time-wasting version by Google: This is just to remind myself how to do this simple thing. I got the information from here (via Google).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekend, buy</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2008/03/weekend-buy.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2008 19:51:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2008/03/weekend-buy.html/</guid>
      <description>This weekend I bought three books:
Bill Evans: How My Heart Sings (Bill Evans: Vida y Obra), Martian Chronicles, by Ray Bradbury (Crónicas Marcianas) and The Lebanese Cookbook (a spanish edition). I have already finished Bradbury&amp;rsquo;s, I enjoyed it a lot. A masterpiece in science-fiction. In one of its short stories there is a poem by Lord Byron:
 So we&amp;rsquo;ll go no more a roving
so late into the night</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meat Loaf (and Jim Steinman)</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2008/02/meat-loaf-and-jim-steinman.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 19:32:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2008/02/meat-loaf-and-jim-steinman.html/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, I was looking after some song lyrics (don&amp;rsquo;t remember exactly which song they belong to), and went into some of these web&amp;rsquo;s that give you &amp;ldquo;you may also like this&amp;rdquo; links. Well, I looked into the lyrics of &amp;ldquo;For Crying Out Loud&amp;rdquo;, by Meat Loaf (who I hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard about, ever). This are the lyrics, and as almost all Steinman&amp;rsquo;s-Meat Loaf songs, they are quite long. Just read the first few verses if you don&amp;rsquo;t feel like reading:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>