<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Memory on mostlymaths.net</title>
    <link>https://mostlymaths.net/tags/memory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Memory on mostlymaths.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 09:30:33 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mostlymaths.net/tags/memory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2021#23 Readings</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2021/10/202123-readings.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 09:30:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2021/10/202123-readings.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As usual, skipping an edition means a longer collection later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aprende a recordarlo todo: el método del palacio de la memoria</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2012/03/aprende-recordarlo-todo-el-metodo-del.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 16:47:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2012/03/aprende-recordarlo-todo-el-metodo-del.html/</guid>
      <description>Cortesía de Shanidar
Puedes leer la versión inglesa de este post aquí: Learn to remember everything: the memory palace method
En este post os voy a enseñar cómo recordar a la perfección una lista. No importa la longitud de la lista: puede ser tu lista de la compra de 10 artículos, o una lista con 50, 100 o incluso 1000 cosas. Y en un próximo post, cómo aplicar este método para aprender idiomas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mind Palace Memory Technique (or: what I&#39;&#39;m watching on TV lately)</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2012/03/mind-palace-memory-technique-or-what-im.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 20:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2012/03/mind-palace-memory-technique-or-what-im.html/</guid>
      <description>Caveat: some of the links appearing in this post are affiliate links to Amazon.com If you buy anything from them, I get a small commission. As always, I only link to stuff I like. If you want to support (ever so slightly) this blog, buy something. If you don&amp;rsquo;t want, don&amp;rsquo;t do it ;)
Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching an interesting TV series. Sherlock, the modern version of Conan Doyle&amp;rsquo;s stories and novels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Books I have Read in 2011: Perfect Gifts for Geeks!</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/12/good-books-ive-read-in-2011-perfect.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2011 21:29:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/12/good-books-ive-read-in-2011-perfect.html/</guid>
      <description>Taken from Flickr
  In case you have not realised it yet, I&amp;rsquo;m a pretty prolific reader. Online reading (and having an iPad) have slowed down the number of books I read in a given year, and I don&amp;rsquo;t go to the lengths of my girlfriend (who is about to reach her goal of reading 102 books in this year,) I&amp;rsquo;m nevertheless a frequent reader.
This year I&amp;rsquo;ve read several good books that I&amp;rsquo;d like to share with you, after all, if you are reading this probably our tastes overlap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mental Drawer: Never miss an idea again</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/09/mental-drawer-never-miss-idea-again.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 13:45:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/09/mental-drawer-never-miss-idea-again.html/</guid>
      <description>This was posted to my mail newsletter a few months ago. Subscribe now if you want to receive this kind of content to your inbox. I won&amp;rsquo;t spam you, promise.
When do you have your best ideas? If you are anything like me, I have my best ideas when I can&amp;rsquo;t act upon them. While I&amp;rsquo;m falling asleep or while I&amp;rsquo;m taking a shower. And a lot of them get lost forever, I always think I&amp;rsquo;ll remember it next morning, something that never happens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Your Memory Palace Collection</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/05/building-your-memory-palace-collection.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 13:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/05/building-your-memory-palace-collection.html/</guid>
      <description>Picture courtesy of Shanidar
Do you want to have very good memory? I do, in fact I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in it since my school days. There are some techniques that exploit your brain&amp;rsquo;s natural power, and the one I&amp;rsquo;m covering here is the memory palace technique.
I have already written about the memory palace memorisation technique (go and read the previous post if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about), but I did not cover a very important point there: Where can you find memory palaces to use in your memorisation?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus in Language Learning: Doing Two Languages at Once Is a Bad Idea</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/05/focus-in-language-learning-doing-two.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/05/focus-in-language-learning-doing-two.html/</guid>
      <description>From my cheap dictionary
Last February I set myself a goal for these next three months (February, March and April): to learn Gaelic. The time is up and I must confess I have not made a lot of advances. The reasons are plenty, and most are shared with whoever wants to learn a new language. They are even harder for people learning a few languages at once, the kind of language nerds that have way too many Teach Yourself books on languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Facts: Using Mental Associative Chains</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/04/remembering-facts-using-mental.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 21:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/04/remembering-facts-using-mental.html/</guid>
      <description>An image can help your memory&amp;hellip;
For how long?
This is a method I use to complement the memory palace technique to remember facts, either historical, about people or any other subject. It is pretty simple and follows the same principles as the memory palace: you need to make up bizarre images. To memorise facts we just need to attach keys to each fact, and link them to the subject or person we are considering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn to Remember Everything: The Memory Palace Technique</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/03/learn-to-remember-everything-memory.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 21:02:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/03/learn-to-remember-everything-memory.html/</guid>
      <description>Picture courtesy of Shanidar
  You can also browse the best books I have seen on memory techniques and related areas here.
In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll teach you how to have perfect recall of lists of items. Length is not much of an issue, it can be your shopping list if 10 items or it can be a list with 50, 100 or even 1000. And in a forthcoming post I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you how to apply this technique to learning new languages.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
