<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>iPod on mostlymaths.net</title>
    <link>https://mostlymaths.net/tags/ipod/</link>
    <description>Recent content in iPod on mostlymaths.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 17:42:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mostlymaths.net/tags/ipod/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Want to play? Get a MFi controller for Christmas</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2017/11/nimbus-steelseries-mfi-controller-for-christmas.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 17:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2017/11/nimbus-steelseries-mfi-controller-for-christmas.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It would probably be an understatement to say I&amp;rsquo;m not a gamer. Last console I
got was a Game Boy, 22 years ago (IIRC). Never got a gaming PC.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anki and Language Learning: The Spaced Repetition System</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/05/anki-and-language-learning-spaced.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2011 18:50:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/05/anki-and-language-learning-spaced.html/</guid>
      <description>From my cheap dictionary
I first heard of spaced repetition software around 5 or 6 years ago, while browsing around the net. Read about it, found it unappealing and moved on. You know, there are times when you learn about something and dismiss it as not necessary&amp;hellip; and after a while you are lead into it again to find it is wonderful. This is one of such instances.
I have only written two highly visited posts about languages: The Language Switch and How to Train Your Brain to Flip to a New Language (in Bitesize Irish Gaelic, it also appeared in Hacker Monthly, April 2011) and a lot of the commenters suggested me using Anki, Mnemosyne or Supermemo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PlainText: Text Editor with DropBox Sync for Your iPod, iPhone or iPad</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/10/plaintext-text-editor-with-dropbox-sync.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2010 22:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/10/plaintext-text-editor-with-dropbox-sync.html/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: For each sale that is made through the purchase links in this post I get a small commission (that does not affect your final purchase price!). Of course, I&amp;rsquo;d love if you bought any app through these links, but I have tried my best to make my review faithful. I don&amp;rsquo;t want anyone to come later at me and say they were tricked into buying any app and the review was unfaithful to the application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone origami case diagrams</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/07/iphone-origami-case-diagrams.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2010 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/07/iphone-origami-case-diagrams.html/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I saw in my Google Analytics that someone came to this blog looking for &amp;ldquo;Origami iPhone case&amp;rdquo;. As I have a Origami CD case, and several posts on iPhone/iPod Touch games&amp;hellip; it was a page hit. But I thought: if I can have a neat CD case, I can also design a neat origami case for an iPhone! Said and&amp;hellip; done. It took a few tries (and a few days), as you can see below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All hail... Steve Jobs and his iPad?</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/02/all-hail-steve-jobs-and-his-ipad.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 18:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/02/all-hail-steve-jobs-and-his-ipad.html/</guid>
      <description>Made with Sketchbook Mobile&amp;hellip;
in an iPod Touch
All hail hypnotoad&amp;hellip; in real life
I want to start by saying that I might buy an iPad, and definitely like it, in an abstract setting. But I think that Steve Jobs is kind of blind through his own charisma. He likes the iPad&amp;hellip; then it should be liked (and bought) by everyone.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think the iPad is gona be a hit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part of iPad</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/01/part-of-ipad.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2010 19:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/01/part-of-ipad.html/</guid>
      <description>I got linked to Ipad&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;history&amp;rdquo;: Someone on MetaFilter posted a link to my emacs on iPod blog post in the thread about the launch of Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPad.
You may also like
ParseList(ScrambleList(Relateds(Linux,iPod,Mac,emacs)),5)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minix on the iPod: where Linux started</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/01/minix-on-ipod-where-linux-started.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2010 00:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/01/minix-on-ipod-where-linux-started.html/</guid>
      <description>This is where Linux started. Minix, from the bible on operating systems. You can easily install it on minivMac for your iPod, download it from this link and install the disk image in your iPod as usual. Then, unpack the files inside.

Fifteen minutes later&amp;hellip;

When unpacking is finished, just open the MacMinix app, and Minix will be up and running.

By the way, the username for MacMinix is root, and the password is Geheim!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syncing iPod&#39;s vMac and Linux: emacs on iPod Touch</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/01/syncing-ipods-vmac-and-linux-emacs-on.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 00:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/01/syncing-ipods-vmac-and-linux-emacs-on.html/</guid>
      <description>Using emacs on the go in your iPod Touch / iPhone Maybe you remember a previous post on installing vMac, a Mac Plus emulator for the iPod Touch. I did it just for the geek factor&amp;hellip; and for being able to edit things with Emacs. I have emacs installed:

But what&amp;rsquo;s the use of emacs, without files to edit? It didn&amp;rsquo;t bother me&amp;hellip; at first. Keep on reading for how to keep in sync files edited inside the vMac emacs and files in your Linux box, along with the &amp;ldquo;why should I use emacs in my iPod/iPhone?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retro on iPod Touch (2): ScummVM</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/12/retro-on-ipod-touch-2-scummvm.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2009 00:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/12/retro-on-ipod-touch-2-scummvm.html/</guid>
      <description>This is a follow up of my previous post on Retro on iPod Touch. Previously I reviewed Mini vMac Apple Mac Plus emulator. This time also comes an emulator (sort of). ScummVM is self-described as a collection of game engine recreations, and is available for several platforms (Mac, Windows and Linux at least&amp;hellip; also several handhelds and game consoles). For me, its main use is to replay old LucasArts graphical adventures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBSettings for jailbroken iPhone/iPod Touch</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/12/sbsettings-for-jailbroken-iphoneipod.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2009 00:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/12/sbsettings-for-jailbroken-iphoneipod.html/</guid>
      <description>After buying my iPod Touch and playing a little with it, I realised that battery life was a problem, with the WiFi always on. Thus, I was always bringing up Settins-WiFi and turning on and off. There was no easy and quick way to do it&amp;hellip; Until I jailbroke it. I installed SBSettings, and its first use was that. Swipe the upper status bar, and the menu shown above appears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iHold</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/11/ihold.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2009 00:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/11/ihold.html/</guid>
      <description>The free iPod stand  
Right: middle line, left top line
In this post I will explain how to recycle an old credit card to build a stand for your iPod touch / iPhone. You can choose from 3 designs, depending on your preferred inclination.
Here is what you will need:
 A printed version of the shape. Scroll down for the jpg&amp;rsquo;d version A card Scissors Something to write A small file</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retro on iPod Touch (1): Mini vMac</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/11/retro-on-ipod-touch-1-mini-vmac.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/11/retro-on-ipod-touch-1-mini-vmac.html/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I jailbroke my iPod touch. Just for the geek factor, first, as I thought I could get a C compiler on it. I can&amp;rsquo;t yet, so I just have it jailbreaken for a few applications. I&amp;rsquo;ll start my review for a long time loved application in Linux and Mac: Mini vMac.Mini vMac is a hardware emulator, which emulates a whole Mac Plus from the eighties. You just need a real Mac ROM, from a Mac you or someone you know owns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mg &amp; Zile: quick emacs in the command line</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/11/mg-zile-quick-emacs-in-command-line.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/11/mg-zile-quick-emacs-in-command-line.html/</guid>
      <description>From The Design of the Emacs Logo
I guess you may already know I love the emacs text editor, and use it as often as I can to do almost everything I can with it. I even use it in my iPod touch, through minivMac. But there is a small niche where it was a pain: quick editing a file from the command line. Those times when you just want to open one file, change a line, save and close.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I bought an iPod touch</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/10/why-i-bought-ipod-touch.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2009 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/10/why-i-bought-ipod-touch.html/</guid>
      <description>Mathematician, Linux user, already had an iPod (iPod nano), recently bought a netbook. Why did I buy an iPod touch?
Papers for iPhone (7.99€): a organizer for research PDF&amp;rsquo;s with integrated PDF reader (allegedly optimized for research articles), with the ability to sync with the desktop app (29€, less with the 40% discount for students&amp;hellip; still waiting for it to buy it). Well, it lives up the expectations, although the desktop version is strange (used it only once, yet) and the syncing can be hard as the network settings may keep you from syncing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>