<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on mostlymaths.net</title>
    <link>/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on mostlymaths.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 19:37:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-9 Readings of the week (x4)</title>
      <link>/2019/04/2019-9-readings-of-week-x4.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 19:37:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/2019-9-readings-of-week-x4.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You know how you slip once on a habit and everything goes crazy? Well, I’ve been 4 weeks without writing these, so here’s the accumulated reading from 4 weeks. Because, even if I don’t write it, I read a lot anyway. Also, there’s lot of interesting content this “week”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-8 Readings of the week</title>
      <link>/2019/03/2019-8-readings-of-week.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 21:11:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/2019-8-readings-of-week.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This edition has Software engineering, formal methods, fraud, Scala. Expect a similar wide range in the future as well. You can check all my weekly readings by checking the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mostlymaths.net/search/label/ReadingsOfTheWeek&#34;&gt;tag here&lt;/a&gt; . You can also get these as a weekly newsletter by subscribing &lt;a href=&#34;http://eepurl.com/geFw7P&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018: Year in Review</title>
      <link>/2019/01/2018-year-in-review.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/2018-year-in-review.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The year has ended, what has been going on?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Work Clean</title>
      <link>/2018/03/book-review-work-clean.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 23:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/book-review-work-clean.html/</guid>
      <description>Down into some net rabbit hole, I stumbled upon a review of Work Clean. I chuckled: a productivity book, philosophizing about how cook’s approach to preparation (mise en place) would fix all our problems? Bring it on, I have a long commute.
Actually, I found the book surprisingly good if you stick to the practical side and discard the hyperbole. As an occasional home cook with a big dose of planning and OCD built into me, I got the point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017: Year in Review</title>
      <link>/2018/01/2017-year-in-review.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 15:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/2017-year-in-review.html/</guid>
      <description>I am trying to make these posts a tradition (even if a few days late). I thought 2016 had been a really weird and fun year, but 2017 has beaten it easily. And I only hope 2018 will be even better in every way. For the record, when I say we, it means Laia and me unless explicitly changed.
Work Everything work related has gone up. More work, better work, more interesting work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Books I&#39;ve Read in 2011: Perfect Gifts for Geeks!</title>
      <link>/2011/12/good-books-ive-read-in-2011-perfect.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2011 21:29:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/12/good-books-ive-read-in-2011-perfect.html/</guid>
      <description>Taken from Flickr
  In case you have not realised it yet, I&amp;rsquo;m a pretty prolific reader. Online reading (and having an iPad) have slowed down the number of books I read in a given year, and I don&amp;rsquo;t go to the lengths of my girlfriend (who is about to reach her goal of reading 102 books in this year,) I&amp;rsquo;m nevertheless a frequent reader.
This year I&amp;rsquo;ve read several good books that I&amp;rsquo;d like to share with you, after all, if you are reading this probably our tastes overlap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you Feel the Smell of Burning Wood? Pyrography Box Beta</title>
      <link>/2010/12/do-you-fell-smell-of-burning-wood.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2010 21:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/12/do-you-fell-smell-of-burning-wood.html/</guid>
      <description>Santa brought me the gift I wanted for Christmas: a pyrograph. In case you don&amp;rsquo;t know, a pyrograph is a tool to draw over wood, by burning it.
As you may already know, I love drawing (in particular, ink drawing). This is similar: you don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of control over tone and a mistake can ruin the drawing.
This was the first time I used one, and to test how it worked I decided to draw a Celtic knot over a wooden box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commented Version of the LaTeX File to Create PDF ebooks and A6 Booklets</title>
      <link>/2010/12/commented-version-of-latex-file-to.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 14:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/12/commented-version-of-latex-file-to.html/</guid>
      <description>Below you can find a commented version of the LaTeX template I used to create two free ebooks and A6 booklets. Now you can tweak it as much as you like it!
The syntax highlighted TeX code comes from the htmlize package in emacs, to keep with my emacs 30 Day Challenge.
\\documentclass\[9pt,openany,final\]{memoir} % Set the font size with 9pt. Openany states that a chapter may start % in either page (recto or verso in publishing language).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating pdf ebooks with LaTeX (With Two Free Examples: Art of War &amp; How to Live on 24 Hours a Day)</title>
      <link>/2010/11/creating-pdf-ebooks-with-latex-with-two.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2010 21:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/11/creating-pdf-ebooks-with-latex-with-two.html/</guid>
      <description>If you are looking for the sample ebooks, scroll down a little (and don&amp;rsquo;t forget to subscribe if you have not done this already!)
I started to look for ways to use LaTeX for doing ebooks very recently. My plan is to write an ebook on productivity and time management, with no deadline. I strive to make it the book I&amp;rsquo;d love to read when I started reading about time management&amp;hellip; And this means I&amp;rsquo;ll need quite a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating A6 Booklets in 7 Easy Steps</title>
      <link>/2010/11/creating-a6-booklets-in-7-easy-steps.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 00:13:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/11/creating-a6-booklets-in-7-easy-steps.html/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer:Some link in this post are affiliate links. For each sale that is made through the purchase links in this post I get a small commission (that does not affect your final purchase price!). Of course, I&amp;rsquo;d love if you bought a book through these links, but keep in mind they are in the public domain (and I&amp;rsquo;ll post them in pdf soon). I don&amp;rsquo;t want anyone to come later at me and say they were tricked into buying the book and then realising it was available for free!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Development for Smart People: A Not So Short Review</title>
      <link>/2010/09/personal-development-for-smart-people.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/09/personal-development-for-smart-people.html/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: For each sale that is made through the purchase links in this post I get a small commission (that does not affect your final purchase price!). Of course, I&amp;rsquo;d love if you bought this book through these links, but I have tried my best to make my review faithful. I don&amp;rsquo;t want anyone to come later at me and say they were tricked into buying the book and the review was unfaithful to the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winning Against Your Reading List</title>
      <link>/2010/08/winning-against-your-reading-list.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2010 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/08/winning-against-your-reading-list.html/</guid>
      <description>A nice warm Sunday afternoon, I wanted something cold to drink and a good book to read in my garden. I glanced at my pile of books beside the door, the books I grab to read in the train to my office, a pile of 8 books. Then I remembered I had a few books in the library I wanted to read, another pile, 10 books. As I went down and put them all over the table, I realised I had a few books more in the computer room, 3 books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vladimir Arnol&#39;d one of the greatest mathematicians of 20th century</title>
      <link>/2010/06/vladimir-arnold-one-of-greatest.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/06/vladimir-arnold-one-of-greatest.html/</guid>
      <description>Most of you may not know who Vladimir Arnold (Владимир Арнольд, also written as Vladimir Arnol&amp;rsquo;d) was, but for me his death on 3rd June 2010,was some kind of landmark. I own two books by him (Mathematical aspects of classical and celestial mechanics [1] and Mathematical methods of classical mechanics [2]), and are quite high in my list of most checked books, at least when I was starting my journey into the realm of dynamical systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St. George: International book day</title>
      <link>/2010/04/st-george-international-book-day.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2010 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/04/st-george-international-book-day.html/</guid>
      <description>The 23rd of April is a very special day in Catalonia. The legend of Saint George, in the Catalan version happens in a small town called Montblanc, and when the knight kills the Dragon from its spilled blood grows a red rose he gave to the princess. Since medieval times, men give their a rose to his significant other, and in 1923 something was added to this story.
A bookseller wanted to spice the celebration, and as Miguel de Cervantes and William Shakespeare died on this same day, he promoted the giving of books as a present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 9 Best Programming Books I Have Read (so far)</title>
      <link>/2010/04/9-programming-books-i-have-read-and.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2010 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/04/9-programming-books-i-have-read-and.html/</guid>
      <description>Below you can find a non exhaustive list of the best programming books I have read so far. I have read a lot more books about programming, but most of them I read and promptly forgot about them. I am reading currently a few more (Code Complete, Thinking Forth), and maybe they can make it into a list like this that my future self writes.
And now, the list of the best programming books I have read so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slicing scannings</title>
      <link>/2009/09/slicing-scannings.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2009 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/09/slicing-scannings.html/</guid>
      <description>Last year our department got a nice and shiny Xerox WorkCentre, with scan+mail capabilities. Wonders of technology, now I can scan those chapters I use from books that weigth tons. But&amp;hellip; of course, the machine scans two pages each time, and thus creates a double bound PDF.
And this doesn&amp;rsquo;t work well with my way to print booklets, so a working solution was to use ghostscript and ImageMagick from the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old books&#39; scent</title>
      <link>/2009/08/old-books-scent.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2009 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/08/old-books-scent.html/</guid>
      <description>I love the smell of old (really old, but not dusty) books. It reminds me of some kind of vanilla scent, that is only to be found in them. I smelled it a few weeks ago, when I bought Conrad&amp;rsquo;s Heart of Darkness, second hand 1972 Penguin Modern Classics edition (3€) in a second hand bookstore in Göttingen (Germany).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy paperback book binding how-to</title>
      <link>/2009/04/easy-paperback-book-binding-how-to.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2009 15:29:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/04/easy-paperback-book-binding-how-to.html/</guid>
      <description>Softcover binding your own books is easier than you think
Bookbinding for dummies As of late, I have been printing quite a lot of long mathematical papers, and a few free pdf-books, or tutorials. And I wanted them properly bound, but didn&amp;rsquo;t want them so much as to pay for it. A few months ago, I found this tutorial on hardback binding. Although the tutorial, method and result are great, it is quite a lengthy effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekend, buy</title>
      <link>/2008/03/weekend-buy.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2008 19:51:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/03/weekend-buy.html/</guid>
      <description>This weekend I bought three books:
Bill Evans: How My Heart Sings (Bill Evans: Vida y Obra), Martian Chronicles, by Ray Bradbury (Crónicas Marcianas) and The Lebanese Cookbook (a spanish edition). I have already finished Bradbury&amp;rsquo;s, I enjoyed it a lot. A masterpiece in science-fiction. In one of its short stories there is a poem by Lord Byron:
 So we&amp;rsquo;ll go no more a roving
so late into the night</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>