<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Games on mostlymaths.net</title>
    <link>https://mostlymaths.net/tags/games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Games on mostlymaths.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 19:30:33 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mostlymaths.net/tags/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2020#66 Readings</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2020/12/202066-readings.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 19:30:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2020/12/202066-readings.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last of 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019#10 Readings of the week</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2019/04/2019-10-readings-of-week.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 11:39:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2019/04/2019-10-readings-of-week.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software engineering, psychology, generative art. Expect a similar wide range in the future as well. You can check all my weekly readings by checking the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mostlymaths.net/search/label/Readings&#34;&gt;tag here&lt;/a&gt; . You can also get these as a weekly newsletter by subscribing &lt;a href=&#34;http://eepurl.com/geFw7P&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019#9 Readings of the week (x4)</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2019/04/2019-9-readings-of-week-x4.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 19:37:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2019/04/2019-9-readings-of-week-x4.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You know how you slip once on a habit and everything goes crazy? Well, I’ve been 4 weeks without writing these, so here’s the accumulated reading from 4 weeks. Because, even if I don’t write it, I read a lot anyway. Also, there’s lot of interesting content this “week”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want to play? Get a MFi controller for Christmas</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2017/11/nimbus-steelseries-mfi-controller-for-christmas.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 17:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2017/11/nimbus-steelseries-mfi-controller-for-christmas.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It would probably be an understatement to say I&amp;rsquo;m not a gamer. Last console I
got was a Game Boy, 22 years ago (IIRC). Never got a gaming PC.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picking up Backgammon</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2015/03/picking-up-backgammon.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 12:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2015/03/picking-up-backgammon.html/</guid>
      <description>The links to Amazon and The Book Depository are affiliate links. If you purchase like 50 copies I may afford a coffee :D

From Flickr
It all started after reading If you can’t choose, pick at random at Aeon.co. It delves into how choosing at random can be best in some cases. Give it a read, it is interesting. Among the HackerNews comments about this submission there were some mentions about choosing at random in real life, and to the novel The Dice Man (Amazon | Book Depository).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Again and Again: Playing Go</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/11/again-and-again-playing-go.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2011 22:28:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/11/again-and-again-playing-go.html/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been playing the game of Go (also known as weiqi or baduk) on and off for almost 10 years. In case you don’t know, Go is a board game with very old roots, that can be traced back to at least 2500 years ago, probably a lot more. Very popular in Japan (known as Go or Igo), Korea (baduk) and China (weiqi), it has been slowly spreading among the west during the last century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mirror Rubik Cube: It Just Looks Gorgeous</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/11/mirror-rubik-cube-it-just-looks.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 18:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/11/mirror-rubik-cube-it-just-looks.html/</guid>
      <description>Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it look nice?
Last week Laia and me went to a toy/book/stuff shop to buy a music stand. Practising guitar without a music stand was starting to feel rather odd. While we were there, we bought several more items, among them an old time favourite from myself: a mirror rubik cube. An addition to my keychain cube, SuperCube, 5x5 cube and Rubik dodecahedron. I had only seen it online, from Amazon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retro on iPod Touch (2): ScummVM</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/12/retro-on-ipod-touch-2-scummvm.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2009 00:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/12/retro-on-ipod-touch-2-scummvm.html/</guid>
      <description>This is a follow up of my previous post on Retro on iPod Touch. Previously I reviewed Mini vMac Apple Mac Plus emulator. This time also comes an emulator (sort of). ScummVM is self-described as a collection of game engine recreations, and is available for several platforms (Mac, Windows and Linux at least&amp;hellip; also several handhelds and game consoles). For me, its main use is to replay old LucasArts graphical adventures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperoid a.k.a. SDLRoids</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/07/hyperoid-aka-sdlroids.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2009 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/07/hyperoid-aka-sdlroids.html/</guid>
      <description>Screenshots!
Back when I was in school, I had a really nice game in my 80286 computer, under Windows 3.1. Yes, it was 15 years ago&amp;hellip; The game was Hyperoid, by Edward Hutchins. When I got my first Pentium with Windows 95, I longed that game&amp;hellip; and the 3.1. version didn&amp;rsquo;t work completely OK in it. Anyway I played&amp;hellip; then found Hyperoid95. I even recompiled it, to add firepower (the author of this version cut the fire speed).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nethack</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/05/nethack.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/05/nethack.html/</guid>
      <description>I &amp;ldquo;discovered&amp;rdquo; Nethack a month or so ago, while being bored to death (after three unsuccessful attempts in proving something) in my office.

Myself with my dog Hachi
I play the MacOs Tiles (or QT) version, which can be found in Nethack.org, configured for ASCII color play. The configuration file is a file called .nethackrc in your home directory, mine looks like:
 OPTIONS=!autopickup,ascii_map, color, hilite_pet, lit_corridor, showexp, showscore, boulder:0;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
