<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iceland on mostlymaths.net</title>
    <link>https://mostlymaths.net/tags/iceland/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iceland on mostlymaths.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 21:15:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mostlymaths.net/tags/iceland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Not Only the Politicians: This country is completely fucked up</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2012/06/its-not-only-politicians-this-country.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 21:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2012/06/its-not-only-politicians-this-country.html/</guid>
      <description>Beware, in what follows I rant. All figures come from Wikipedia or similar and are expressed with many zeroes and also in written form to make clear what a billion may be.
If you are a regular reader of mostlymaths.net, you&amp;rsquo;ll be aware that I don&amp;rsquo;t write a lot about current subjects. In fact, I actively try not to write about what&amp;rsquo;s going on at the moment, one notable exception may be a post I wrote about Mesut Özil&amp;rsquo;s stellar debut in the 2010 World Cup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTTI: 11 – A fjord day and visit to Ísafjörður</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/06/road-trip-through-iceland-day-10-fjord.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 09:45:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/06/road-trip-through-iceland-day-10-fjord.html/</guid>
      <description>In Back to the Future, Doc sets the clock in the DeLorean to a day 25 years in the future. Today (2010, 6th July) is that day.
 Today was a really amazing day. It was very sunny, and we visited Ísafjörður, a city that stole our hearts.
Holmavík&amp;rsquo;s Witchcraft Museum, Reykjanes We started our day with breakfast and taking a quick picture of Drangsnes&#39; Rock troll. It does not look like a troll for us, but anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTTI: 10 – Hvítserkur</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/06/road-trip-through-iceland-day-10.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/06/road-trip-through-iceland-day-10.html/</guid>
      <description>As you may remember, yesterday we were not happy with our guest house. And in addition to what we saw yesterday, today our breakfast was d––n late. When you are driving around a country trying to be on time everywhere, you wake up early and drive a lot. If your breakfast is late, you are bound to either go faster (not a good idea in Iceland) or get to places later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTTI: 9 - Goðafoss and Hólar</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/06/road-trip-through-iceland-day-9-goafoss.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/06/road-trip-through-iceland-day-9-goafoss.html/</guid>
      <description>Hólar&amp;rsquo;s church, if I&amp;rsquo;m not wrong
I&amp;rsquo;ve been procrastinating a lot with this post. Although it may not look like this from the pictures (or even the text), this was one of the worse days in our trip. Uneventful, visiting not-so-interesting places and with a lousy guest house at the end of the day. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if you find if interesting! If not, the next post will be, don&amp;rsquo;t worry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anki and Language Learning: The Spaced Repetition System</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/05/anki-and-language-learning-spaced.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2011 18:50:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/05/anki-and-language-learning-spaced.html/</guid>
      <description>From my cheap dictionary
I first heard of spaced repetition software around 5 or 6 years ago, while browsing around the net. Read about it, found it unappealing and moved on. You know, there are times when you learn about something and dismiss it as not necessary&amp;hellip; and after a while you are lead into it again to find it is wonderful. This is one of such instances.
I have only written two highly visited posts about languages: The Language Switch and How to Train Your Brain to Flip to a New Language (in Bitesize Irish Gaelic, it also appeared in Hacker Monthly, April 2011) and a lot of the commenters suggested me using Anki, Mnemosyne or Supermemo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTTI: 8 - From Mývatn to Husavik visiting Ásbyrgi and Dettifoss</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/04/road-trip-through-iceland-day-8-from.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2011 20:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/04/road-trip-through-iceland-day-8-from.html/</guid>
      <description>No more gas ahead
Leaving Mývatn was a little dull. We saw a pair of handcraft stores that looked really interesting&amp;hellip; And they were closed until 11! No way we could spend so much time waiting. We fueled, bought vanillated skyr for the route and took the road to Dettifoss. This is one of those places where you definitely have to fuel, there is no other gas station in 130km.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTTI: 7 - From Egilsstaðir to Mývatn passing through Hverir</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/04/road-trip-through-iceland-day-7-from.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 22:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/04/road-trip-through-iceland-day-7-from.html/</guid>
      <description>The Myvatn area
This weeks post in the Iceland road trip series comes a little late: Saturday was a relaxation day, and Sunday I posted about how relaxing Saturday felt. As such, I didn&amp;rsquo;t put the time to typeset this post until Friday was looming! I think I got a little out of hand adding pictures to this post&amp;hellip; But the Mývatn area is impressive and I wanted to show it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTTI: 6 - East Fjords, Egilsstaðir and Borgarfjörður</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/04/road-trip-through-iceland-day-6-east.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 17:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/04/road-trip-through-iceland-day-6-east.html/</guid>
      <description>Geese in the East Fjords, Iceland
In the last 2 weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve had a big surge of visits and new subscribers, following the rise in HackerNews of my old post Timeboxing: You Will Work Like Never Before and of my newer post Learn to Remember Everything: The Memory Palace Technique. To put in situation, last July my girlfriend and me made a road trip around Iceland, and I wrote everything we did each day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTTI: 5 - Ingolfshöfði and Jökulsárlón (again)</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/03/road-trip-through-iceland-day-5.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 20:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/03/road-trip-through-iceland-day-5.html/</guid>
      <description>Happy World Water Day! Luckily the post due for today was a lot of water in it, iced water sparkling of thousand years old blue ice. This was supposed to be our puffin visit day&amp;hellip; But schedules played badly on us and we could not make it. We just made another round of Jökulsárlón icebergs while collecting shoreside rocks.
Expat tales While we were having breakfast we saw another guest in the lovely guesthouse at Hofell&amp;hellip; and he surprised us by asking if we were Catalans, in Catalan!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTTI: 4 - Two magic places, Svartifoss and Jökulsárlón</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/03/road-trip-through-iceland-day-4-two.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 12:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/03/road-trip-through-iceland-day-4-two.html/</guid>
      <description>Svartifoss, Iceland
Today (i.e. this day in our trip) was Laia&amp;rsquo;s birthday, and one of our personal landmarks in this trip, as we visited our favourite places: Svartifoss, my special place and Jökulsárlón, a place Laia loves. We spent almost all day in these two places and driving around, but they are probably two of the most remarkable experiences of our road trip in Iceland.
Kirkjugolf and Skaftafell Today we managed to visit the church&amp;rsquo;s floor, the Kirkjugolf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road Trip Around Iceland: The Index</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/03/road-trip-around-iceland-index.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 13:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/03/road-trip-around-iceland-index.html/</guid>
      <description>Dynjandi waterfall, Iceland
This is the journal of our road trip around Iceland, what we did each day as we circled the island through the Ring Road. This series of posts started on February 2011, and is so far ongoing, posting once a week from our annotations and pictures. Bookmark this page if you want to come back to see what&amp;rsquo;s new.
Road Trip Around Iceland, Day 1: Reykjavik - the city I&amp;rsquo;d like to live</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTTI: 3 - Waterfalls and Glaciers</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/03/road-trip-through-iceland-day-3.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 12:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/03/road-trip-through-iceland-day-3.html/</guid>
      <description>After visiting the wonders of the Golden Circle, we kept driving eastward getting into the region of waterfalls and glaciers. The day began with 2000 Icelandic krónur of fuel, that for 1/4 of the tank. Expensive, but not as expensive as one may guess, from prices in Spain. It continued with the first sighting of lambs in the middle of the road&amp;hellip; Get used to that, it is very common!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTTI: 2 - The Golden Circle (Thingvellir, Geysir and Gullfoss)</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/02/road-trip-through-iceland-day-2-golden.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 23:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/02/road-trip-through-iceland-day-2-golden.html/</guid>
      <description>The Kerid crater. Don&amp;rsquo;t miss it!
This was the official first day. We did a quick packing and preparing in our room and headed downstairs. Breakfast time, and we were amused to find a bunch of Spanish hiking tourists, with a Spanish guide. Had a wonderful breakfast with some tips from the guide: Beware of falling over the side of the road. Why? Because you can be easily distracted by the landscape!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTTI: 1. Reykjavik - the city I&#39;d like to live</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/02/road-trip-through-iceland-day-1.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 00:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/02/road-trip-through-iceland-day-1.html/</guid>
      <description>﻿ / 64.133; -21.933

After a huge delay, this is the first of a few posts about our road trip to Iceland last June and July. While we were there, I wrote a journal about what we did and saw each day, and this is the extended version (with pictures!)
We arrived to Keflavík International Airport (its terminal is named Leifur Eiríksson after the European discoverer of North America), really late: our plane needed refueling before departure and it ate quite a lot of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Language Switch (or how my brain seems to work when learning languages)</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/01/language-switch-or-how-my-brain-seems.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 00:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/01/language-switch-or-how-my-brain-seems.html/</guid>
      <description>From my cheap dictionary
I love learning languages. Since I picked my first Teach yourself English (in Spanish) from my grandparents place when I was 10 years old, I have been fascinated by languages and language learning, first human languages and then also by computer languages. Aside from English, Spanish and Catalan I can defend myself in German and French (enough to get directions and keep simple conversations up, although the last time I was in Germany all Germans I talked to said I could keep up pretty well&amp;hellip; Sure they are polite!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleeping Where the Sun Never Sets and Other Oddities</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/10/sleeping-where-sun-never-sets-and-other.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2010 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/10/sleeping-where-sun-never-sets-and-other.html/</guid>
      <description>As you may remember, Laia and me spent three weeks in Iceland for holidays two months ago. This is the sixth (and last) post in the series Things you should read before travelling to Iceland. If you came here directly don&amp;rsquo;t forget to read the previous post in this series
Eating in Iceland (if you are not an Icelander)
Road Trip Through Iceland
How Is Iceland&amp;rsquo;s Weather?
Iceland&amp;rsquo;s Water: the Best Water in the World</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shopping in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/shopping-in-iceland.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 20:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/shopping-in-iceland.html/</guid>
      <description>As you may remember, Laia and me spent three weeks in Iceland for holidays two months ago. This is the fifth post in the series Things you should read before travelling to Iceland. If you came here directly don&amp;rsquo;t forget to read the previous post in this series
Eating in Iceland (if you are not an Icelander)
Road Trip Through Iceland
How Is Iceland&amp;rsquo;s Weather?
Iceland&amp;rsquo;s Water: the Best Water in the World</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iceland&#39;s Water: the Best Water in the World</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/icelands-water-best-water-in-world.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/icelands-water-best-water-in-world.html/</guid>
      <description>As you may remember, Laia and me spent three weeks in Iceland for holidays two months ago. This is the fourth post in the series Things you should read before travelling to Iceland. If you came here directly don&amp;rsquo;t forget to read the previous post in this series
Eating in Iceland (if you are not an Icelander)
Road Trip Through Iceland
How Is Iceland&amp;rsquo;s Weather?
If I had to gamble before going to Iceland, I would have thought tap water would be horrible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Is Iceland&#39;s Weather?</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/how-is-icelands-weather.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2010 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/how-is-icelands-weather.html/</guid>
      <description>The Sun street
As you may remember, Laia and me spent three weeks in Iceland for holidays two months ago. This is the third post in the series Things you should read before travelling to Iceland. If you came here directly don&amp;rsquo;t forget to read the previous post in this series
Eating in Iceland (if you are not an Icelander)
Road Trip Through Iceland
Weather is not as bad as you may expect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road Trip Through Iceland</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/road-trip-through-iceland.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/road-trip-through-iceland.html/</guid>
      <description>re
Iceland is one of the few places
where you can park inside a
volcano
As you may remember, Laia and me spent three weeks in Iceland for holidays two months ago. You can read the day-by-day exploration with plenty of pictures by browsing the tag Iceland, which accounts our road trip. This is the second post in the series Things you should read before travelling to Iceland. If you came here directly don&amp;rsquo;t forget to read the previous post in this series</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icelandic Waterfall and Rock Wallpaper</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/waterfall-and-rock-wallpaper.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/waterfall-and-rock-wallpaper.html/</guid>
      <description>This is a picture I shot in Iceland, in the Dynjandi Waterfall. If a caption is needed, it would be Never give up. Click the thumbnails to download the high resolution images.

Dynjandi Waterfalls
I have not set any download tracking, thus I don&amp;rsquo;t know if you are downloading these: Please, if you download one of these wallpapers, please leave a comment in the form below!
If you like this wallpaper, please share in StumbleUpon or Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eating in Iceland (if you are not an Icelander)</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/08/eating-in-iceland-if-you-are-not.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 19:40:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/08/eating-in-iceland-if-you-are-not.html/</guid>
      <description>As you may remember, Laia and me spent three weeks in Iceland for holidays two months ago. This is the first post in the series Things you should read about before travelling to Iceland. Be sure to stay tuned for the following posts!
First I would like to say you one thing about Iceland&amp;rsquo;s food: don&amp;rsquo;t be scared! They don&amp;rsquo;t eat anything odd, except for a few national foods which are not that usual: hákari (rotten shark meat) and hrutspungar (pickled ram testicles).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things You Should Read before Travelling to Iceland</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/08/things-you-should-read-before.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2010 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/08/things-you-should-read-before.html/</guid>
      <description>Interesting things to know before going to Iceland As you may remember, Laia and myself went to Iceland for a 2 and half weeks trip last June-July. It was a wonderful experience, managed by the wonderful (and helpful!) people at Nordic Visitor. This is the first post in a series named Things you should read before travelling to Iceland. In these posts I will cover the following (I will add links to the individual posts here as I write them, bookmark this page!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 100 most common words in Icelandic, automatically generated from Wikipedia</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/05/100-most-common-words-in-icelandic-more.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/05/100-most-common-words-in-icelandic-more.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The file can be downloaded at the end of the post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may already know, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mostlymaths.net/2010/08/things-you-should-read-before.html&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m travelling to Iceland this
July&lt;/a&gt;,
and started learning Icelandic a few months ago. It advances slowly but firmly,
but I found a problem:when you are self-learning a new language, an invaluable
tool is a list of most common words.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
