<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fractals on mostlymaths.net</title>
    <link>https://mostlymaths.net/tags/fractals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fractals on mostlymaths.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 19:37:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mostlymaths.net/tags/fractals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2019-9 Readings of the week (x4)</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2019/04/2019-9-readings-of-week-x4.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 19:37:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2019/04/2019-9-readings-of-week-x4.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You know how you slip once on a habit and everything goes crazy? Well, I’ve been 4 weeks without writing these, so here’s the accumulated reading from 4 weeks. Because, even if I don’t write it, I read a lot anyway. Also, there’s lot of interesting content this “week”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Processing from Scala</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2018/03/processing-and-scala.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 17:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2018/03/processing-and-scala.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had always wanted to play with Processing (after leafing through &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Processing-Programming-Handbook-Designers-Artists/dp/026202828X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1520004355&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=processing+handbook&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=rbersblog-20&amp;amp;linkId=08457cedf1bdf882589a65f2a56c181b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The
Processing
Handbook&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Visualizing-Data-Explaining-Processing-Environment/dp/0596514557/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=rbersblog-20&amp;amp;linkId=3aa08467e0b53ce75e261bf7a9d7cf3c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Visualizing
Data&lt;/a&gt;
some years ago). My general dislike for Java or the JVM made me just play a
short amount of time with &lt;code&gt;processing.js&lt;/code&gt; something around 2011 (there was a
&lt;em&gt;native&lt;/em&gt; processing.js application for iOS, I used it for a while on my iPad and
iPod Touch).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling of exponent overflow in GNU APL and Dyalog APL (on Mac)</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2015/04/handling-of-exponent-overflow-in-gnu.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 11:29:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2015/04/handling-of-exponent-overflow-in-gnu.html/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I started trying a pre-beta release of Dyalog APL (now available as &amp;ldquo;full beta&amp;rdquo;) for Mac. Fellow Mac users, looks like we are in for a treat after so much time of only having GNU APL and the pretty expensive APLX. Now Mac APL lovers, users and aficionados will have a competitive, commercial option. At last!
I started with the usual 1+1, ⍳ 10 , ⍴ ⍳ 10 to check it worked as expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mandelbrot set in one line of APL</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2014/01/the-mandelbrot-set-in-one-line-of-apl.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 20:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2014/01/the-mandelbrot-set-in-one-line-of-apl.html/</guid>
      <description>Is this line noise?

⍉&amp;#39; *&amp;#39;[⍎&amp;#39;1+0&amp;lt;|z&amp;#39;,(∊150⍴⊂&amp;#39;←c+m×m&amp;#39;),&amp;#39;←c←(¯2.1J¯1.3+(((2.6÷b-1)×(¯1+⍳b))∘.+(0J1×(2.6÷b-1)×(¯1+⍳b←51))))&amp;#39;] Nope. This is not line noise, but a complete APL program to display the Mandelbrot set in glorious ASCII, with asterisks and spaces just like Brooks and Matelski did a long time ago while studying Kleinian groups (it&amp;rsquo;s a short paper, read it someday). I&amp;rsquo;ll explain in (a lot, I hope) detail this line in a few moments. So, what&amp;rsquo;s APL first?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gift: A Quadratic Julia Set for Iceland&#39;s National Day</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/06/gift-quadratic-julia-set-for-icelands.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2011 00:05:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/06/gift-quadratic-julia-set-for-icelands.html/</guid>
      <description>Click to open in a new window/tab and then right click to Save as
Today is Iceland&amp;rsquo;s National Day (commemorating their independence day and the date of birth of Jón Sigurðsson), and to commemorate it I share this image with everyone.
I computed this image a long, long time ago (using the Distance Estimator Method, paralellised with PVM using 16 computers, it took just 2 minutes). The full file is a 30MB pdf, which I printed large-size, and sits in my office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On a productivity down</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/06/on-productivity-down.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2010 12:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/06/on-productivity-down.html/</guid>
      <description>A week without writing here. A week with little thesis related work done. But it has also been a week with ideas and things and such. You know, two weeks ago I was in Dresden for a conference. Lots of parallel sessions, and quite a few time to think. This post is mostly a digest from my life bookmarks for these two weeks.
Several complex dynamic ideas: Unrelated to my thesis, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about them these days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External rays &amp; Lavaurs algorithm</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/11/external-rays-lavaurs-algorithm.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/11/external-rays-lavaurs-algorithm.html/</guid>
      <description>As you may remember, I spent quite some time this August with Lavaurs algorithm for the topological identification of the circle corresponding to the Mandelbrot set. After that, I spent quite some more trying to do pictures of external rays to show side by side. I was not able… and then found Mandel.
 Thanks to Mandel, LISP and my Lavaurs code
  Really nice program, with lots and lots of options (and I met the programmer, which happens to be also mathematician, we met at a conference).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scribus for mathematical posters</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/11/scribus-for-mathematical-posters.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/11/scribus-for-mathematical-posters.html/</guid>
      <description>As you may already know, I presented a poster at a conference recently, and did the set up with Scribus, the texts with LaTeX with the Beamer and Beamerposter packages.
 Setting up
  Note from 2019: I can&amp;rsquo;t find the final version of that poster, only a modified version from a few months later for another conference.
The first piece of advise, is to set page guides where needed (in the Page menu, you can put them at a certain numerical place, and then move them along) and then Snap to guides in the same menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: emacs fractal zoomer</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/10/project-emacs-fractal-zoomer.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/10/project-emacs-fractal-zoomer.html/</guid>
      <description>I have several (really, a lot) of programs to compute different images for my article, amusement, anything. And all of them require a change-and-try approach for zooming. The first I wrote needed to be finished quickly&amp;hellip; so I just hard-coded in the source the parameters. And this program turned to be the basis for all others&amp;hellip; And now each zoom requires some calculations and recompile.
A time ago I decided to do something about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infinite complexity</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/10/infinite-complexity.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2009 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/10/infinite-complexity.html/</guid>
      <description>Just 5 excerpts of it
Related posts:
And &amp;ldquo;e&amp;rdquo; appears from nowhere!9 programming books I have read and somewhat liked&amp;hellip;
C code juicer: detecting copied programming assignments
Cron, diff &amp;amp; wget: Watch changes in a webpage
8 reasons for re-inventing the wheel as a programmer
Approximating images with randomly placed translucent triangles
ParseList(ScrambleList(Relateds(Linux, Programming)),10)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to work</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/09/back-to-work.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/09/back-to-work.html/</guid>
      <description>From flickr
September is to months as Monday is to weekdays
September is again here, like a new year in more than a sense. I have no new &amp;ldquo;New Year&amp;rsquo;s promises&amp;rdquo;, since the beginning of the year. In fact, most of the things I wanted to do are already done, on the way to be done or I gave up. Well, let&amp;rsquo;s summarize what I shall do these three months to end 2009</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lavaurs algorithm</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/08/lavaurs-algorithm.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2009 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/08/lavaurs-algorithm.html/</guid>
      <description>These days I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy programming a version of Lavaurs algorithm for the idenfication of circle chords: the abstract Mandelbrot set.
The images don&amp;rsquo;t look like much, but the output of the program is nicer: it outputs an Encapsulated PostScript file which looks sharper. But when converting to png with ImageMagick some distortion appeared.
 Lavaurs chords, depth 13 cutoff
   Lavaurs chords, depth 5
   Lavaurs chords, depth 13</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teleworking in August</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/08/teleworking-in-august.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2009 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/08/teleworking-in-august.html/</guid>
      <description>Lavaurs algorithm on course
Like almost every year, August comes with a lot of pending To Do lists&amp;hellip; This year, it is choking full, mostly of work related issues, and some unknotted threads waiting to be finished. And in two and a half weeks I&amp;rsquo;ll head for Paris, and then my &amp;ldquo;vacation&amp;rdquo; is over.
Yesterday I wasted my morning: bought my orange belt, set up the external monitor for my netbook, configured the printer, fotocopied two pages of a book and drank an horchata with a friend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Siegel disk wallpaper</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/07/siegel-disk-wallpaper.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/07/siegel-disk-wallpaper.html/</guid>
      <description>As I already did with Douady Rabbits, here is another dynamical plane, this time corresponding to a Siegel disk in an entire transcendental family in a parameter corresponding to a polynomial-like region.

Siegel disk in an ETF, available below as wallpaper
Siegel disk for desktop background 1280x800
Siegel disk for desktop background 1024x768
You can also buy a poster version here.
If you liked it, or have whatever else to say please leave a comment, digg, stumble or whatever you feel like doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Douady rabbit wallpaper</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/03/douady-rabbit.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/03/douady-rabbit.html/</guid>
      <description>I have been experimenting with exponential-power potentials in my fractal images as of late, and by far the best results have been these. You can download it as a desktop wallpaper, hope you enjoy it. This Douady rabbit appears as a capture zone for a critical value in an exponential family.

Douady rabbit in an exponential family, available below as wallpaper
Douady rabbit for desktop background 1280x800
Douady rabbit for desktop background 1024x768</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>