<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drawing on mostlymaths.net</title>
    <link>https://mostlymaths.net/tags/drawing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drawing on mostlymaths.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 18:39:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mostlymaths.net/tags/drawing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2019#20,21,22 Readings of the week</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2019/07/2019202122-readings-of-week.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 18:39:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2019/07/2019202122-readings-of-week.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been pretty busy lately, and although reading doesn’t stop, my writing sometimes takes a hiatus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data engineering, adtech, history, apple. Expect a similar wide range in the future as well. You can check all my weekly readings by checking the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mostlymaths.net/search/label/ReadingsOfTheWeek&#34;&gt;tag here&lt;/a&gt; . You can also get these as a weekly newsletter by subscribing &lt;a href=&#34;http://eepurl.com/geFw7P&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019#9 Readings of the week (x4)</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2019/04/2019-9-readings-of-week-x4.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 19:37:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2019/04/2019-9-readings-of-week-x4.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You know how you slip once on a habit and everything goes crazy? Well, I’ve been 4 weeks without writing these, so here’s the accumulated reading from 4 weeks. Because, even if I don’t write it, I read a lot anyway. Also, there’s lot of interesting content this “week”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019#1 Readings of the week</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2019/01/2019-1-readings-of-week.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2019/01/2019-1-readings-of-week.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you know me, you&amp;rsquo;ll know I have a quite extensive reading list. I keep it in &lt;a href=&#34;https://getpocket.com/&#34;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt;, and is part of my to do stored in &lt;a href=&#34;https://culturedcode.com/things/&#34;&gt;Things3&lt;/a&gt;. It used to be &lt;em&gt;large&lt;/em&gt; (hovering around 230 items since August) but during Christmas it got out of control, reaching almost 300 items.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold Brew Yerba Mate</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2015/06/cold-brew-yerba-mate.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2015/06/cold-brew-yerba-mate.html/</guid>
      <description>Thermometers are already hitting 29°C with temperature feelings around 32 or 33. It’s this time of the year when I need cold drinks to keep me alive. I’m not a big soda fan (except when I’m on Finland in the Nordic Go Academy camp, they are so stocked on soda that I’m dragged in,) so my go-to drink is usually freshly squeezed lemonade with some ice cubes and sometimes a pinch of soda to make it fizz (and make it less acid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing (Really) Nothing</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/04/doing-really-nothing.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 09:45:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/04/doing-really-nothing.html/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I did nothing. Absolutely, really nothing.
 And it felt great. Before yesterday, my usual weekend was filled of what I thought was doing nothing, but far from it. I wrote posts, programmed, read a lot online and caught up with what was going in the A-List Blogger Club forum. Did some laundry, folded the clothes. All this (well, except for the laundry part) under the assumption that doing what you love does not tire you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving on holidays</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/06/leaving-on-holidays.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/06/leaving-on-holidays.html/</guid>
      <description>Today I am leaving on holiday&amp;hellip; Destination: Iceland. It is funny, because we arranged everything (accomodation, car rental and such) just two weeks before Eyjafjallajökull started spitting ash. It have been a few months wondering whether we could make it to Iceland and come back&amp;hellip; Fortunately the little volcano took a pause and here we go.
I have a few scheduled posts for this few weeks (I&amp;rsquo;ll be back around 16th July) but I will be again posting more frequently after I am back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NGO volunteer deployment tactics</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/05/ngo-volunteer-deployment-tactics.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2010 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/05/ngo-volunteer-deployment-tactics.html/</guid>
      <description>- Mr(s) Red Square is doomed to donate</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All hail... Steve Jobs and his iPad?</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/02/all-hail-steve-jobs-and-his-ipad.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 18:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/02/all-hail-steve-jobs-and-his-ipad.html/</guid>
      <description>Made with Sketchbook Mobile&amp;hellip;
in an iPod Touch
All hail hypnotoad&amp;hellip; in real life
I want to start by saying that I might buy an iPad, and definitely like it, in an abstract setting. But I think that Steve Jobs is kind of blind through his own charisma. He likes the iPad&amp;hellip; then it should be liked (and bought) by everyone.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think the iPad is gona be a hit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fountain pen ink drawing</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/01/fountain-pen-ink-drawing.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 00:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/01/fountain-pen-ink-drawing.html/</guid>
      <description>I got this bookfor Christmas (more or less), and started to read and draw from it a few days ago. It is amazing what small hints can do to a messy drawing. The barrel, in particular, started as a messy outline (from the barrel in the book) and the final result looks pretty convincing (for me, at least).

First drawing

Second drawing

Third drawing

Fourth drawing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolutionary approximation of a Christmas postcard</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/12/evolutionary-approximation-of-christmas.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 19:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/12/evolutionary-approximation-of-christmas.html/</guid>
      <description>If you liked it, leave a comment, digg, stumble
or whatever you feel like doing
Stochastic hill-climbing algorithm to approximate a picture by triangles (algorithm and source code). This image contains 48 images out of 1000, from iterating for 11000 generations the evolution code. The source image is the last square in the tile set.
Bon Nadal!
Feliz Navidad!
Merry Christmas!
Joyeux Nöel!
Buon Natale!
Frohe Weihnachten!
Mutlu Noeller!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future in Mathematics</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/11/future-in-mathematics.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/11/future-in-mathematics.html/</guid>
      <description>With Sketchbook Mobile
The concepts of &amp;ldquo;future&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;job stability&amp;rdquo; or even &amp;ldquo;location&amp;rdquo; are quite fuzzy when in Mathematics. I think I don&amp;rsquo;t know any PhD student who knows what he will be doing in 3 years, what he will be working on (not what he will be researching, but working&amp;hellip;) or even where he will be.
  1-2 years of Master+Master thesis
  2-6 years of PhD thesis (3-4 years PhD grant+maybe some associated professor, 1-4 years)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rasterbator: online posterizer for @home printing</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/05/rasterbator-online-posterizer-for-home.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2009 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/05/rasterbator-online-posterizer-for-home.html/</guid>
      <description>My chair, my fractals (A4) and my Drazen
Petrovic poster (4xA4)
Rasterbator is an online poster maker, for you to print in your own printer. Of course, the results are not as good as full quality posters like these, but they look pretty good when looked from afar. It rasterises an image you upload (or link from anywhere in Internet), does some magic stuff, and the result is a bunch (you decide graphically how many, orientation and other options) of A4 (or Legal) sheets arranged in a nice PDF, which you have to print.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaii Higashiyama</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2008/03/kaii-higashiyama.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 22:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2008/03/kaii-higashiyama.html/</guid>
      <description>Japanese painter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketching</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2007/12/sketching.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2007 13:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2007/12/sketching.html/</guid>
      <description>As you may already know, I enjoy a lot drawing. I usually draw with some kind of mechanical pencil, of HB strength (or one for film writing which is stronger than 3H). As I try to improve the quality of my drawings, I begin to wonder if I really like to draw really well. Yes, I&amp;rsquo;d like to be able to draw perfect faces, but probably I&amp;rsquo;ll be as happy being able to sketch a face that looks like the original one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>