<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SEO on mostlymaths.net</title>
    <link>https://mostlymaths.net/tags/seo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SEO on mostlymaths.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 15:31:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mostlymaths.net/tags/seo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2017: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2018/01/2017-year-in-review.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 15:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2018/01/2017-year-in-review.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am trying to make these posts a tradition (even if a few days late). I thought 2016 had been a really weird and fun year, but 2017 has beaten it easily. And I only hope 2018 will be even better in every way. For the record, when I say &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt;, it means Laia and me unless explicitly changed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find Search Engine Rankings... via the Command Line</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2013/05/find-search-engine-rankings-via-command.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 18:33:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2013/05/find-search-engine-rankings-via-command.html/</guid>
      <description>Via pixelfrenzy@flickr
Beware! The software described here is just for personal and very light use. Its use beyond purely recreational value is against Google Search terms of service, and I don&amp;rsquo;t want you or anyone to step that line. Any use of this code is at your own risk.
Well, after this scary paragraph, lets get to the real meat. Which boils down to just a few lines of bash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to the magic of Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2012/10/an-introduction-to-magic-of-google-tag.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 18:41:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2012/10/an-introduction-to-magic-of-google-tag.html/</guid>
      <description>If you want to read a quick overview of this in Spanish, check my post about GTM at DoctorMetrics.
Google has just unveiled a new tool: Google Tag Manager. I have spent a few hours playing with it (both before and after official release.) And it&amp;rsquo;s awesome! Or at least, it has quite a lot of awesomeness, hidden behind a seemingly simple interface.
Its main feature is the fact that you can get away with just a piece of included code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>