<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trips on mostlymaths.net</title>
    <link>https://mostlymaths.net/tags/trips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Trips on mostlymaths.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 15:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mostlymaths.net/tags/trips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2018: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2019/01/2018-year-in-review.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2019/01/2018-year-in-review.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The year has ended, what has been going on?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2018/01/2017-year-in-review.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 15:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2018/01/2017-year-in-review.html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am trying to make these posts a tradition (even if a few days late). I thought 2016 had been a really weird and fun year, but 2017 has beaten it easily. And I only hope 2018 will be even better in every way. For the record, when I say &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt;, it means Laia and me unless explicitly changed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleeping Where the Sun Never Sets and Other Oddities</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/10/sleeping-where-sun-never-sets-and-other.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2010 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/10/sleeping-where-sun-never-sets-and-other.html/</guid>
      <description>As you may remember, Laia and me spent three weeks in Iceland for holidays two months ago. This is the sixth (and last) post in the series Things you should read before travelling to Iceland. If you came here directly don&amp;rsquo;t forget to read the previous post in this series
Eating in Iceland (if you are not an Icelander)
Road Trip Through Iceland
_How Is Iceland&amp;rsquo;s Weather?_
____Iceland&amp;rsquo;s Water: the Best Water in the World____</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shopping in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/shopping-in-iceland.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 20:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/shopping-in-iceland.html/</guid>
      <description>As you may remember, Laia and me spent three weeks in Iceland for holidays two months ago. This is the fifth post in the series Things you should read before travelling to Iceland. If you came here directly don&amp;rsquo;t forget to read the previous post in this series
Eating in Iceland (if you are not an Icelander)
Road Trip Through Iceland
_How Is Iceland&amp;rsquo;s Weather?_
____Iceland&amp;rsquo;s Water: the Best Water in the World____</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iceland&#39;s Water: the Best Water in the World</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/icelands-water-best-water-in-world.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/icelands-water-best-water-in-world.html/</guid>
      <description>As you may remember, Laia and me spent three weeks in Iceland for holidays two months ago. This is the fourth post in the series Things you should read before travelling to Iceland. If you came here directly don&amp;rsquo;t forget to read the previous post in this series
Eating in Iceland (if you are not an Icelander)
Road Trip Through Iceland
_How Is Iceland&amp;rsquo;s Weather?_
If I had to gamble before going to Iceland, I would have thought tap water would be horrible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Is Iceland&#39;s Weather?</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/how-is-icelands-weather.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2010 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/how-is-icelands-weather.html/</guid>
      <description>The Sun street
As you may remember, Laia and me spent three weeks in Iceland for holidays two months ago. This is the third post in the series Things you should read before travelling to Iceland. If you came here directly don&amp;rsquo;t forget to read the previous post in this series
Eating in Iceland (if you are not an Icelander)
Road Trip Through Iceland
Weather is not as bad as you may expect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road Trip Through Iceland</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/road-trip-through-iceland.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/road-trip-through-iceland.html/</guid>
      <description>re
Iceland is one of the few places
where you can park inside a
volcano
As you may remember, Laia and me spent three weeks in Iceland for holidays two months ago. You can read the day-by-day exploration with plenty of pictures by browsing the tag Iceland2010, which accounts our road trip. This is the second post in the series Things you should read before travelling to Iceland. If you came here directly don&amp;rsquo;t forget to read the previous post in this series</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icelandic Waterfall and Rock Wallpaper</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/waterfall-and-rock-wallpaper.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/09/waterfall-and-rock-wallpaper.html/</guid>
      <description>This is a picture I shot in Iceland, in the Dynjandi Waterfall. If a caption is needed, it would be Never give up. Click the thumbnails to download the high resolution images.

Dynjandi Waterfalls
I have not set any download tracking, thus I don&amp;rsquo;t know if you are downloading these: Please, if you download one of these wallpapers, please leave a comment in the form below!
If you like this wallpaper, please share in StumbleUpon or Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eating in Iceland (if you are not an Icelander)</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/08/eating-in-iceland-if-you-are-not.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 19:40:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/08/eating-in-iceland-if-you-are-not.html/</guid>
      <description>As you may remember, Laia and me spent three weeks in Iceland for holidays two months ago. This is the first post in the series Things you should read about before travelling to Iceland. Be sure to stay tuned for the following posts!
First I would like to say you one thing about Iceland&amp;rsquo;s food: don&amp;rsquo;t be scared! They don&amp;rsquo;t eat anything odd, except for a few national foods which are not that usual: hákari (rotten shark meat) and hrutspungar (pickled ram testicles).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things You Should Read before Travelling to Iceland</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/08/things-you-should-read-before.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2010 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/08/things-you-should-read-before.html/</guid>
      <description>Interesting things to know before going to Iceland As you may remember, Laia and myself went to Iceland for a 2 and half weeks trip last June-July. It was a wonderful experience, managed by the wonderful (and helpful!) people at Nordic Visitor. This is the first post in a series named Things you should read before travelling to Iceland. In these posts I will cover the following (I will add links to the individual posts here as I write them, bookmark this page!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9&#43;4 fundamental things you should pack in your travels</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/07/94-fundamental-things-you-should-pack.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 19:45:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/07/94-fundamental-things-you-should-pack.html/</guid>
      <description>Being a copilot in Iceland can be either stressing or boring. It depends if you are going to an almost unmarked farm where you will spend the night or just in the middle of an unending straight road. And in the boredom moments, I decided to compile a list of things we had packed and were really useful. I hope this helps you in your next trip!
 Fishing line: Fishing line is quite useful for several things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving on holidays</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/06/leaving-on-holidays.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/06/leaving-on-holidays.html/</guid>
      <description>Today I am leaving on holiday&amp;hellip; Destination: Iceland. It is funny, because we arranged everything (accomodation, car rental and such) just two weeks before Eyjafjallajökull started spitting ash. It have been a few months wondering whether we could make it to Iceland and come back&amp;hellip; Fortunately the little volcano took a pause and here we go.
I have a few scheduled posts for this few weeks (I&amp;rsquo;ll be back around 16th July) but I will be again posting more frequently after I am back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 100 most common words in Icelandic, automatically generated from Wikipedia</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/05/100-most-common-words-in-icelandic-more.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/05/100-most-common-words-in-icelandic-more.html/</guid>
      <description>Scroll down to download the file if you want to skip the how I did it part!
As you may already know, I&amp;rsquo;m travelling to Iceland this July, and started learning Icelandic a few months ago. It advances slowly but firmly, but I found a problem: when you are self-learning a new language, an invaluable tool is a list of most common words. I was able to find the 100 most common words, from a research paper (Íslenskur Orðasjóður - Building a large icelandic corpus).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Den lille havfrue</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/10/den-lille-havfrue.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/10/den-lille-havfrue.html/</guid>
      <description>København, Denmark
Related posts:
ParseList(ScrambleList(Relateds(Maths)),5)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to work</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/09/back-to-work.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/09/back-to-work.html/</guid>
      <description>From flickr
September is to months as Monday is to weekdays
September is again here, like a new year in more than a sense. I have no new &amp;ldquo;New Year&amp;rsquo;s promises&amp;rdquo;, since the beginning of the year. In fact, most of the things I wanted to do are already done, on the way to be done or I gave up. Well, let&amp;rsquo;s summarize what I shall do these three months to end 2009</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paris Space Invaders</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/08/paris-space-invaders.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2009 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/08/paris-space-invaders.html/</guid>
      <description>While on Paris, I spotted several Space Invaders. Sadly, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware enough, as there are plenty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old books&#39; scent</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/08/old-books-scent.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2009 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/08/old-books-scent.html/</guid>
      <description>I love the smell of old (really old, but not dusty) books. It reminds me of some kind of vanilla scent, that is only to be found in them. I smelled it a few weeks ago, when I bought Conrad&amp;rsquo;s Heart of Darkness, second hand 1972 Penguin Modern Classics edition (3€) in a second hand bookstore in Göttingen (Germany).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gauss&#39; grave</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/07/gauss-grave.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/07/gauss-grave.html/</guid>
      <description>Princeps Mathematicorum

Old 10 Deutsche Mark banknote. Gauss depicted along with a normal distribution and 5 historical buildings in Göttingen. The most visible, St. Jacobi&amp;rsquo;s Church (Jacobikirsche).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>