<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Origami on mostlymaths.net</title>
    <link>https://mostlymaths.net/tags/origami/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Origami on mostlymaths.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 22:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mostlymaths.net/tags/origami/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A DIY Origami Notebook to Keep in Your Jeans&#39; Small Pocket</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/01/diy-origami-notebook-to-keep-in-your.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 22:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2011/01/diy-origami-notebook-to-keep-in-your.html/</guid>
      <description>This is the notebook where I keep my to-do list, like the one you can see in the picture in Book Review: Do It Tomorrow. A quick and cheap way to have a small multi-page notebook you can keep always with you. Of course, calling this origami is a small lie, as you have to use scissors.
I read a very good post about going the analog way (How analog rituals can amp your productivity) and this was my tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone origami case diagrams</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/07/iphone-origami-case-diagrams.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2010 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/07/iphone-origami-case-diagrams.html/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I saw in my Google Analytics that someone came to this blog looking for &amp;ldquo;Origami iPhone case&amp;rdquo;. As I have a Origami CD case, and several posts on iPhone/iPod Touch games&amp;hellip; it was a page hit. But I thought: if I can have a neat CD case, I can also design a neat origami case for an iPhone! Said and&amp;hellip; done. It took a few tries (and a few days), as you can see below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origami A5 (booklet size) paper inbox</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/06/origami-a5-booklet-size-paper-inbox.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 14:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/06/origami-a5-booklet-size-paper-inbox.html/</guid>
      <description>One inbox to rule them all Since I started printing everything in A5 booklet format, more and more articles and printed stuff gets scattered over my desk, in this format. Which is really handy for reading and travelling, but not so much for piling over the desk.
A pile of inner stapled A5 is slightly womb&amp;hellip; when there are more than 5 big documents stacked, it can easily fall. And I had several piles over my desktop: To read someday (better sooner than later), current references (papers I am using more than twice a week or so) and past references (the ones that were in the previous category but have not used in a while).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On a productivity down</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/06/on-productivity-down.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2010 12:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2010/06/on-productivity-down.html/</guid>
      <description>A week without writing here. A week with little thesis related work done. But it has also been a week with ideas and things and such. You know, two weeks ago I was in Dresden for a conference. Lots of parallel sessions, and quite a few time to think. This post is mostly a digest from my life bookmarks for these two weeks.
Several complex dynamic ideas: Unrelated to my thesis, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about them these days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origami Flower-Box diagrams</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/05/origami-flower-box-diagrams.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2009 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/05/origami-flower-box-diagrams.html/</guid>
      <description>An English version of my diagrams for the origami flower-box Origami flower-box (Caja-Flor) diagrams, in English. Loosely based upon Kawasaki&amp;rsquo;s rose and a traditional japanese box. Click on the diagrams to get a bigger view of them. It appeared (Spanish version) on the Spanish Origami Association Bulletin, Second Volume, 2008. You can also take a look at my easy origami CD case.
 
It will look like this when finished, closed and opened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to do an (easy) origami CD case</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/05/how-to-do-easy-origami-cd-case.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2009 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2009/05/how-to-do-easy-origami-cd-case.html/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago I was looking for an origami CD case. I found this site (which uses Tom Hull&amp;rsquo;s design). Although it is a quick and neat design for an origami case, I don&amp;rsquo;t like it, it feels like the CD is about to fall. So I tweaked for a while, and came up with this design. It takes a little longer to fold, but holds really firm, and looks nicer after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origami masks</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2008/03/origami-masks.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 14:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2008/03/origami-masks.html/</guid>
      <description>Browsing old posts in Origami Tessellations, I found out about Joel Cooper&amp;rsquo;s origami masks. Here are a few examples taken from these two web pages.
 
They are really amazing&amp;hellip; I hope I can learn how to do that. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to start learning something about origami tessellations, which is a thing I&amp;rsquo;ve always skipped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Satoshi&#39;s Pegasus</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2008/02/satoshis-pegasus.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2008 15:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2008/02/satoshis-pegasus.html/</guid>
      <description>Kamiya Satoshi&amp;rsquo;s Pegasus, folded from a square from A4 standard paper (21x21 cm square). The model is about 8 cm long. Satoshi suggests 25x25 paper, which obviously must be thinner than 80g/m^2. But the model itself is wonderful, although my rendition of may not be worth of it.
PS: Shame on me, for not rendering the head as it must be done (à la Dave Brill&amp;rsquo;s horse). Well, next time, with bigger paper :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketching</title>
      <link>https://mostlymaths.net/2007/12/sketching.html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2007 13:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostlymaths.net/2007/12/sketching.html/</guid>
      <description>As you may already know, I enjoy a lot drawing. I usually draw with some kind of mechanical pencil, of HB strength (or one for film writing which is stronger than 3H). As I try to improve the quality of my drawings, I begin to wonder if I really like to draw really well. Yes, I&amp;rsquo;d like to be able to draw perfect faces, but probably I&amp;rsquo;ll be as happy being able to sketch a face that looks like the original one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
